foreign
[Music]
the fields of balsam root and Lupine are
in full bloom and the wind smells of
lilac I was working the entire day at my
shop and doing all sorts of tedious work
activities that has the sunset I use the
last bit of energy reserves I had to to
go and see the wild Meadows in their
full Glory
all they did was wander about for a bit
and pick some flowers but when I finally
left due to a rainstorm I felt that
today had great value and I was so happy
to have made the effort to go witness
the springtime at its most abundant
this decision got me thinking about how
hard it can be after a long work day to
find time to do what you love or the
motivation for that matter when it's
just so much easier to perpetually put
off goals and passions for Another Day
That Never Comes
maybe we spend a lot of time watching TV
or on our phones and while there's
nothing wrong with this I know it can be
Troublesome when we actually want to do
something different with her time and
just feel too burned out to do so
laughs
[Music]
foreign
come on
I thought I would share a few things
that have helped me but firstly I must
say that it is a perfectly good thing to
rest and do nothing productive with your
time off we don't need to produce
anything to show that we used our time
well and we all need to allow ourselves
quality rest that helps us feel better
the next day we might sometimes feel
shame for taking time just to have fun
or take a nap or simply waste time by
other standards and I think it's so
important to know we have innate value
we don't need to prove it we can just be
however if you're truly wanting to
change your lifestyle a bit and aren't
sure where to begin maybe these ideas
will help but I don't know everyone is
different
[Music]
thank you I know this is an obvious one
but distractions that give us instant
gratification over long-term rewards can
have a strong pull on her time off
limiting these things may be
uncomfortable at first you may find
yourself not wanting to be without them
but over time you'll get used to it and
may find a renewal of interest and
energy to put in other things that bring
you Joy at least for me I found I had
more energy when I simply didn't have
the option of scrolling for hours or
watching TV more than I wished and again
there's nothing wrong with this but it
may help to limit it if you really want
to put time into other projects after I
forced my self-defined Alternative forms
of entertainment I slowly developed the
energy and interest to do them
consistently
[Music]
thank you
I have been wanting to work on this
porch for quite a long time and I just
haven't felt quite up to it so I'm glad
I got it done today I've been wanting to
paint the furniture and put out some new
plants that will thrive in the shade
such as bleeding hearts forget me not
I'm really happy with how it's all
turned out and now that I'm on a bit of
a roll with getting projects done I'm
gonna go make some dried flower art I've
had some flowers pressed between some
books for quite a few weeks so I'm going
to take them out and create some art
pieces with them and share that with you
because it's a bit of my tradition not
only on this channel but a springtime
tradition for myself that I always
create art with the spring flowers so I
will bring you along with me and I'm
going to begin by gathering some lilacs
[Music]
right
foreign
also I find it helpful to develop a
great reverence and value on working on
projects and hobbies that benefit your
mental health perhaps you may not always
want to take a long walk or work on a
mindful hobby but if you know you need
to do it in order to manage stress
improve your memory or feel better it
may help you form the habit
I'm yet to meet someone who wants to do
something that's good for them every day
but if their beliefs align with their
pastimes they see that it is necessary
to thrive even if it's hard sometimes
and of course be patient with your
process it will take time to find what
works for you and what helps motivate
you to make time for your hobbies and
interests sometimes it's just
it's just and I think then we can find
peace and acceptance that we're in a
time of transition and we may be in a
different situation someday and we can
embrace our growth and make what smaller
changes are possible right now perhaps
just start with one small step for me I
found journaling a little every day was
a great first step to feeling like I
accomplished something small for myself
that one achievement motivated me to
make other changes
hello
um this is a project I've been working
on all day today and I have been
enjoying it so much so I wanted to tell
you if it is Springtime where you are
living right now and you have access to
a nursery or you have some house plants
or a bouquet that you can use some of
the flowers for dried flower art that is
a wonderful wonderful craft and just it
looks so beautiful it's really hard to
mess it up to be honest if you're
wondering why I am so close to the
camera and I'm kind of backed up in a
corner it's because I haven't actually
filmed up here in the tree house room
for a very long time I used to do a lot
of Clips up here but it's been a while
because my husband Luke has been working
on renovating this area because he has a
background in construction and he's very
good with Woodworking and he wants to
make this room into a bedroom we hope so
here is why you haven't been up here for
a while there is a lot of things moving
and changing and Luke has been working
on trying to put in some sort of closet
because currently we don't really have
one and there is a very small small room
back there that doesn't even fit a bed
and so we're hoping to move out of that
room at some point and be here so that
is the goal I'll I'll give you an update
once it's done there is your little uh
home update it is all chaos and my cat
loves it there's even a shelf in my way
and so I am looking forward to using
this room once again but in the meantime
I have been focusing energy on
decorating downstairs because that is
what I'm able to do and yes that is
where I got the idea to do kind of my
spring tradition I think at this point
and work on these pressed flower art
designs so apart from that it has been a
fairly busy week and I don't know what
next week is going to look like my
little puppy has a little lump on his
head that has been there for a little
while and the veterinarian said it was
finally time to probably remove it so I
might be having surgery next week so
that has been something that's been a
bit on my mind so we'll see how the next
week goes hopefully everything's okay
but he is doing really well right now
and he's getting a lot of treats and a
lot of extra pets and he's very very
happy I also have been spending quite a
bit of time reading I think I've read
about 50 books this year so far I think
it has been quite shocking to me to have
read so many books I think it's because
I really made an effort to pick up my
book over my phone this year and that
has made a huge difference and I've been
so excited about all the new stories
I've been reading I recently started
painted Devils by Margaret Owen the
cover looks a little bit spooky so I'm
not sure if it's going to be my cup of
tea however I really loved her first
book in the series called little thieves
and it was all inspired by Germanic
folklore and I really enjoyed it so I'm
gonna see how this one goes and I will
keep you updated on all my new reading
Adventures I hope you enjoyed this topic
of this video this week and let me know
if there's any other topics you are
interested in hearing about I know I've
talked about this one before but I did
want to revisit it just because it is a
something that has impacted me greatly
this year you know really trying to put
in new habits and hobbies into my day
that I tended to not have time and
energy for last year last year I was
working three different jobs and I just
felt exhausted all the time and I got
ill as well and so it was just a very
difficult combination that I didn't
share too much about on this channel but
I did make a few videos talking about
how I was just having a hard time
feeling energized and feeling okay and
thankfully I'm starting to feel a lot
better I will always be someone who is
not always feeling very motivated or
energized it is just natural to who I am
but I know that that's something that a
lot of people deal with so that's why I
wanted to talk in this video about at
least a few little things that helped me
find the motivation and the ability to
do at least some things I love every day
because it is so much easier to just get
back from a long work day and just
vegetate and that if you have every
right to do that I think that we
sometimes shame ourselves for taking the
rest we need and if you need rest you
need to rest and that is something that
I did a lot of last year and there were
times that I felt sorry for myself
because I wasn't getting projects done
that I really wanted to but I wish if I
could go back to encourage myself and
comfort my myself perhaps things aren't
going exactly how you may have wished
but you can do the best you can by
taking care of yourself and so that was
what I wanted to reiterate in regards to
this video I definitely found spending a
little bit more time meditating on my
life of today versus tomorrow what do I
want to do with these days this
incredible gift that has been given to
me developing that philosophy of not
what you were doing but why you were
doing it in regards to your lifestyle I
think is what will help make a permanent
change for me I used to force myself to
try to eat healthier food because I
thought that it was just good for me and
it's what I should do and I should just
force it but it wasn't until I got quite
ill and then I wasn't feeling well
realized I wanted to put Great Value in
living along and healthy life at least
as healthy as I'm capable of living and
that that philosophy developing that
reason why I was making those Lifestyle
Changes is what actually made it happen
not just forcing myself to do it without
any other reason but just that I should
do it or someone told me I should do it
defining what you want to be doing with
your life not what someone else told you
you should be doing or what society
makes you feel like you should be doing
but what you really really want to do I
think can be so helpful for me it was
about following my spirit and seeing
where that takes me and what lifestyle
changes I feel I not only want to do but
I need to do for my mental health for my
Stress Management for feeling better
altogether feeling like the days are
full of more fulfillment
that made all the difference the why is
so much more important I think than the
what you are doing and I hope you have a
wonderful wonderful week and you maybe
try a new craft or hobby this week or
just try to do something a little bit
different that you usually don't do
maybe just spend a little time writing
down how you feel in a journal or going
on a walk or learning something new and
let me know if there's any other topics
you'd like me to cover in a video and I
will see you very soon sending so much
love goodbye
foreign
[Music]